625 W, 1st Street, # 112 Tempe, AZ 85281

# Gaurav Kumar Srivastav

https://www.linkedin.com/pub/gauravsrivastav/36/950/8bb

+1-480-452-2756 gaurav.srivastav@asu.edu

### **SUMMARY**

Graduate student with 4+ years of professional experience in end to end software development in an agile environment. Individual as well as team performer with strong communication and problem solving skills. Good understanding of data structures, algorithms, service-oriented architecture and object oriented programming.

# **EDUCATION**

Master of Computer Science, Arizona State University, Tempe - GPA 3.83/4.00

May 2016 (expected)

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science, Cochin University of Science And Technology, India

Apr 2010

### LANGUAGE AND TECHNOLOGY

**Programming Languages:** Java, C#, Python, C, XML, HTML, JavaScript, and JQuery.

Framework/IDE: Spring MVC, .NET 3.5/4.0, Eclipse, STS, Visual Studio, Hadoop, Apache Spark, Junit.

Databases and Platforms: MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL.

Version Control Tools: Git, SVN, Team Foundation Server.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Development Engineer, Intern Amazon Web Services (AWS S3)

Amazon.com, Seattle, USA.

May 2015 - Aug 2015

• Developed a Java service named Messy (Massive Exception Scanner Service, Yay!) which scans the massive application log of multiple services of AWS S3 (Simple Storage Service) and generates the histogram of exception report periodically. Service successfully runs as a full-fledged application producing metrics which are used to add alarms on S3 services experiencing high application log exceptions counts.

# **Computer Programmer**

Arizona State University, Tempe, USA.

Oct 2014 - May 2015,

Aug 2015- Present

• Part of the 3 member technical team at Learning Sciences Institute, ASU. Developed a game based tutoring system for adults that aims to contribute to adult literacy research through an adaptive literacy tool that will provide automated feedback during game based activities. Also implemented a scoring system to award certain amount of points to each user based on choices they select.

# **Analyst**

# British Telecommunications, Bangalore, India

Jan 2013- Jul 2014

Designed and developed web based order fulfillment application called as Single Interface using .Net framework. Implemented many web
based reporting functionalities for generating multiple order/task reports, Wrote SQL jobs to archive the customer data, did performance
improvement by optimizing many SQL procedures, functions and views and also acted as configuration controller and component designer
for the project.

# **System Engineer**

Aug 2010- Dec 2012

# BMW Financial Services, Seoul, South Korea

• Developed windows and web based retail finance system called NLS (New lending suite) for BMW financial services which facilitates the functionality of loan servicing for a retail finance system. Encrypted the sensitive customer information using AES encryption mechanism as per the law of South Korea. Integrated the NLS with web based interface called Owner Circle where all the registered customers are allowed to update their personal details (Bank details, Address etc.) and they can also view and print their monthly and future invoices.

Infosys Limited, Pune, India

## ACADEMIC PROJECTS

# **Secure Banking System**

Fall 2015

• Developed a secure banking system (SBS) to facilitate banking transactions and user account management through the Internet. The project emphasizes on providing security by using powerful security techniques such as One Time Password, SSL/TSL (HTTPS), Public Key Infrastructure (PKI), Multi-factor Authentication and reCaptcha. Project is developed using Spring MVC, Hibernate, MySQL, Apache Tomcat, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

### **Geo-Spatial Operations Implementation on Apache Spark**

Spring 2015

• Implemented the Geo-spatial operations like Geometry Union, Convex Hull, Farthest Pair, Closest Pair, Spatial Join, Spatial Aggregation and Spatial Range in Apache Spark. Input file was a huge set of points of the form (x,y). The input file was loaded on HDFS. Spark transformations and actions are optimally used to yield better efficiency of the implementation on a cluster of six nodes. The cluster was just a bunch of laptops connected over wireless network.

# **Go Shopping**

Fall 2014

• Developed a .Net based web application with SOAP and REST services built over Wal-Mart API, Google news API, GeoData API and Weather services API. Application consumes these SOAP and REST services to establish an online shopping solution with facility for users to search for products based on keywords and different categories, to provide offers and deals, to get nearest store details on map and also to suggest different products.